http://www.calhort.org/privacy-policy/

What’s HappeningCOVID-19 ResponseClassesGarden Show 2020Garlic FairMaster GardenerOpen GardensPlant ShareI Caught the Ad!Get InvolvedAbout MembershipVolunteerDonateSponsorAdvertiseMembershipWhy Join?Join the SocietyFriends of the SocietyResourcesAsk a GardenerCommunity GardensFind a Community GardenFind a DiscountGardeningGardening FAQsOur PublicationsPerennial PlantMember LoginArticle IndexAsk an ExpertCalgary GardeningGarden CoachingMembers’ ForumMember TalkOpen Gardens VideosOpen GardensPlant DatabasePlant ShareSociety GovernanceYour AccountYour ProfileAbout UsOur HistoryMission and VisionContact UsPrivacy PolicyHome > Privacy PolicyIntroductionHello,Calgary Horticultural Society (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the http://calhort.org website (the “Service”).This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Who we are Our website address is http://calhort.org.We are the Calgary Horticultural Society.  The organization is led by Executive Director, Colleen McCracken, email: executivedirector@calhort.orgTelephone: 403.287.3469Our Vision: Gardening for Life!Mission: To encourage gardening for the enhancement of our environment and quality of life.Values:Put the fun into gardeningConnect and support new and experienced gardenersPromote learning and successful gardeningWork with our environment to minimize our footprintLead in making Calgary a city of gardening excellenceThe Society is a registered charity. Its mandate has a strong focus on gardening education and offers Calgarians the knowledge and skills to do it well. We are driven by the belief that as the gardening community grows, the city’s quality of life is enhanced, and so is the environment. Gardening is a healthy activity growing in popularity in Calgary and across the country. What personal data we collect and why we collect itWe collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.Types of data collectedPersonal dataWhile using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:Email addressFirst name and last namePhone numberAddress, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, CityCookies and Usage DataCommentsWhen visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.MediaIf you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.Contact formsIf you submit a contact form for Open Gardens your name, address, phone number, email address, and submitted photographs, will be retained for the duration of the program, unless a request is received to remove it. As a featured Open Garden, your name and address are shared with our membership so they may visit your garden on the scheduled Open Gardens date. After the event, this information is no longer displayed on our website.Cookies and usage dataUsage DataWe may also collect information about how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g., IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.CookiesWe use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.Examples of Cookies we use:Session Cookies. We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.Preference Cookies. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.Security Cookies. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.Use of dataCalgary Horticultural Society uses the collected data for various purposes:To provide and maintain the ServiceTo notify you about changes to our ServiceTo allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do soTo provide customer care and supportTo provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the ServiceTo monitor the usage of the ServiceTo detect, prevent and address technical issuesEmbedded content from other websitesArticles on this site may include embedded content (e.g., videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.AnalyticsWe may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.Google AnalyticsGoogle Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=enWho we share your data withWe do not share your personal information. We do provide our sponsors with aggregated site usage information collated by Google Analytics.How long we retain your dataIf you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.Revenue Canada requires purchase records be retained for seven years. However, we do not retain any credit card information.Membership information is retained indefinitely.For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.What rights you have over your dataIf you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.Where we send your dataVisitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.Transfer of dataYour information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.If you are located outside Canada and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to Canada and process it there.Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.Calgary Horticultural Society will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.Privacy Policy contact informationIf you have questions about our privacy policy, please contact the Society’s Executive Director by email: executivedirector@calhort.org or telephone: 403.287.3469. How we protect your dataThe security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.To access her/his personal profile information, a member enters two-factor authentication. Staff and volunteers are required to sign a Confidentiality Agree. We contract services that offer us expertise in ensuring our data is secure.Service providersWe may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.What data breach procedures we have in placeIf ever we discover that our data systems have been breached, we will inform our membership in as timely a manner as feasible, by email or phone.Legal requirementsCalgary Horticultural Society may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:To comply with a legal obligationTo protect and defend the rights or property of Calgary Horticultural SocietyTo prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the ServiceTo protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the publicTo protect against legal liabilityChildren’s privacyOur Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.Changes to this Privacy PolicyWe may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.Effective Date: July 3, 2018 JOIN NOW DONATE
Spotlight
Give the Gift of Membership this Holiday SeasonGreat Gifts for Gardeners. It’s that time of year when a gardener’s thoughts turn to … gift giving! It is also time for the Society’s seasonal membership drive. This past growing season, many people tried gardening for the first time or returned to it after … Read MoreGenerously Supported By
